[
    {   
        "id" : "1",
        "question" :"How do ocean spell in Japanese?",
        "option" :[
        "Umi",
        "Taki",
        "Mori",
        "Sora"
            ],
           
            "correctAnswer" : "Umi"  
    },
    {   
        "id" : "2",
        "question" :"How do you say good morning in Japanese?",

        "option" : [
        "Konbanwa",
        "Ohayo",
        "Oyasumi",
        "Konnichiwa"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Ohayo"
        
    },
    {   
        "id" : "3",
        "question" :"How to say Family in Japanese?",
        "option" : [
        "Tomodachi",
        "Sensei",
        "Kazoku",
        "Keisatsu"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Kazoku"
    },
    {
        "id" : "4",
        "question" :"Choose correct sentence",
        "option" :[
        "Watashi ni Dan desu",
        "Hon wo yomimasu",
        "Gohan kara tabemasu",
        "Betonamu wo ikimasu"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Hon wo yomimasu"
    },
    {
        "id" : "5",
        "question" :"Which prefecture below belongs to Shikoku?",
        "option":[
        "Osaka",
        "Hokkaido",
        "Yamagata",
        "Kagawa"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Kagawa"
    },
    {
        "id" : "6",
        "question" :"Which food below is Osaka feature cuisine?",
        "option":[
        "Takoyaki",
        "Udon",
        "Soba",
        "Tofu"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Takoyaki"
    },
    {
        "id" : "7",
        "question" :"Japan is made up of islands. How many islands does Japan have in total?",
        "option":[
        "6,852",
        "380",
        "6",
        "14,125"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "14,125"
    },
    {
        "id" : "8",
        "question" :"What is a traditional Japanese inn called?",
        "option" :[
        "Onsen",
        "Ryokan",
        "Capsule",
        "Hanok"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Ryokan"
    },
    {
        "id" : "9",
        "question" :"We all know Tokyo is the largest city in terms of population, but where is the second biggest?",
        "option":[
        "Kyoto",
        "Osaka",
        "Yokohama",
        "Nagoya"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Yokohama"
    },
    {
        "id" : "10",
        "question" :"Japan’s total population is approx. 127 million, but which European country is similar in size according to landmass?",
        "option":[
        "France",
        "Germany",
        "Spain",
        "United Kingdom"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "id" : "11",
        "question" :"How tall is the iconic Mount Fuji?",
        "option":[
        "3,776m",
        "3,776ft",
        "2,893m",
        "2,893ft"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "3,776m"
    },
    {
        "id" : "12",
        "question" :"Few ‘original’ castles remain from the Edo period of 1603 to 1868. How many still exist today?",
        "option":[
        "8",
        "12",
        "19",
        "23"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "12"
    },
    {
        "id" : "13",
        "question" :"What is the top operational speed of the Shinkansen aka The Bullet train?",
        "option":[
        "200kmph",
        "260kmph",
        "320kmph",
        "400kmph"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "320kmph"
    },
    {
        "id" : "14",
        "question" :"Japan is renowned for its incredible food. Which city is nicknamed the ‘kitchen of Japan’?",
        "option":[
        "Osaka",
        "Kobe",
        "Fukuoka",
        "Nagasaki"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Osaka"
    },
    {
        "id" : "15",
        "question" :"Which quintessentially Japanese dish actually originates from Portugal?",
        "option":[
        "Sushi",
        "Okonomiyaki",
        "Ramen",
        "Tempura"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Tempura"
    },
    {
        "id" : "16",
        "question" :"Which sacred animal is known for wandering through Nara Park?",
        "option" :[
        "Gazelle",
        "Deer",
        "Red Squirrel",
        "Horse"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Deer"
    },
    {
        "id" : "17",
        "question" :"Hokkaido’s red-crowned cranes are iconic. In which part of the island can they be seen all year round?",
        "option" :[
        "Shiretoko Penisula",
        "Kushiro Marshland",
        "Akan-Nashu National Park",
        "Nice try! It's not in Hokkaido"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Kushiro Marshland"
    },
    {
        "id" : "18",
        "question" :"In which prefecture can you find the hot spring-bathing Japanese macaque aka snow monkey?",
        "option":[
        "Ishikawa",
        "Kagoshima",
        "Okinawa",
        "Nagano"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Nagano"
    },
    {
        "id" : "19",
        "question" :"In which region would you find the city of Sendai?",
        "option":[
        "Honshu",
        "Chugoku",
        "Tohoku",
        "Shikoku"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Tohoku"
    },
    {
        "id" : "20",
        "question" :"What does the red circle on the Japanese flag represent?",
        "option":[
        "The red Komodo Dragon",
        "The sun",
        "The imperial Japanese Army",
        "The Emperor of Japan"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The sun"
    },
    {
        "id" : "21",
        "question" :"Where is the 'Awa Odori' festival held?",
        "option":[
        "Yamaguchi",
        "Tokushima",
        "Akita",
        "Aomori"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Tokushima"
    },
    {
        "id" : "22",
        "question" :"What is 'Shinto'?",
        "option" :[
        "A city",
        "A type of train",
        "A religion",
        "A traditional dish"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A religion"
    },
    {
        "id" : "23",
        "question" :"What is the most popular western nickname for Japan?",
        "option":[
        "Land of the Rising Sun",
        "The red dragon",
        "Down Under",
        "Land of Fire"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Land of the Rising Sun"
    },
    {
        "id" : "24",
        "question" :"In which city can you find Godzilla Road?",
        "option":[
        "Nara",
        "Nagoya",
        "Osaka",
        "Tokyo"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "id" : "25",
        "question" :"How is the culture of cuteness in Japan called?",
        "option":[
        "Hawaii",
        "Kawaii",
        "Hakaii",
        "Kahaii"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Kawaii"
    },
    {
        "id" : "26",
        "question" :"If you are taking the fastest train from Tokyo to Osaka, how long will it take?",
        "option":[
        "2h30",
        "3h30",
        "4h30",
        "5h30"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "2h30"
    },
    {
        "id" : "27",
        "question" :"Which of the following is NOT a symbol of Shinto, Japan's indigenous religion?",
        "option":[
        "Sword",
        "Mirror",
        "Jewel",
        "Vase"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Vase"
    },
    {
        "id" : "28",
        "question" :"Which of the following Japanese terms refers to graphic novels or comics made in Japan?",
        "option":[
        "Origami",
        "Anime",
        "Manga",
        "Novella"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Manga"
    },
    {
        "id" : "29",
        "question" :"Which Japanese wine is traditionally made from fermented rice?",
        "option":[
        "Genmaicha",
        "Sake",
        "Uroncha",
        "Aojiru"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Sake"
    },
    {
        "id" : "30",
        "question" :"Which of the following is NOT a Japanese dish?",
        "option":[
        "Sushi",
        "Udon",
        "Kimchi",
        "Ramen"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Kimchi"
    },
    {
        "id" : "31",
        "question" :"Which of these is the national currency of Japan?",
        "option":[
        "Yen",
        "Yuan",
        "Dollar",
        "Won"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Yen"
    },
    {
        "id" : "32",
        "question" :"Japan is home to how many active volcanoes in total?",
        "option":[
        "9",
        "28",
        "52",
        "111"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "111"
    },
    {
        "id" : "33",
        "question" :"Which flower symbolises the Japanese Imperial family and Emperor?",
        "option":[
        "Cherry Blossom",
        "Chrysanthenum",
        "Hydrangea",
        "Wisteria"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Chrysanthenum"
    },
    {
        "id" : "34",
        "question" :" The Samurai are remembered for wielding curved swords in battle, but what were they called?",
        "option":[
        "Tantou",
        "Odachi",
        "Katana",
        "Wakizashi"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Katana"
    },
    {
        "id" : "35",
        "question" :"In Japan, it's customary to do what upon entering somebody's house?",
        "option":[
        "Shake the owner's hand",
        "Remove your shoes",
        "Bow respectfully",
        "Light an incense stick"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Remove your shoes"
    },
    {
        "id" : "36",
        "question" :"What was Tokyo called during the Edo era?",
        "option":[
            "Tokyo-san",
            "Edo",
            "Takeshi",
            "Kabukicho"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Edo"
    },
    {
        "id" : "37",
        "question" :"What do waiters say when welcoming guests in restaurants?",
        "option":[
            "Arigato",
            "Irasshaimase",
            "Sayonara",
            "Itterasshai"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Irasshaimase"
    },
    {
        "id" : "38",
        "question" :"What does Sushi mean?",
        "option":[
            "Raw fish",
            "Sour-tasting rice",
            "Shark food",
            "Fresh roll"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Sour-tasting rice"
    },
    {
        "id" : "39",
        "question" :"What are the women pearl divers called in Japan?",
        "option":[
            "Nando",
            "Ama",
            "Eto",
            "Okama"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ama"
    },
    {
        "id" : "40",
        "question" :"What is the name of the current Emperor of Japan?",
        "option":[
            "Naruhito",
            "Akihito",
            "Shotoku",
            "Akiko"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Naruhito"
    },
    {
        "id" : "41",
        "question" :"What is the name of the current Prime Minister of Japan?",
        "option":[
            "Fumio Kishida",
            "Shinzo Abe",
            "Itou Hirobumi",
            "Suga Yoshihide"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Fumio Kishida"
    },
    {
        "id" : "42",
        "question" :"What is Uji city in Kyoto known for?",
        "option":[
            "Mochi",
            "Mizu-mochi",
            "Matcha",
            "Senbei"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Matcha"
    },
    {
        "id" : "43",
        "question" :"Where is Shirakawago located?",
        "option":[
            "Nagano",
            "Gifu",
            "Shiga",
            "Mie"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Gifu"
    },
    {
        "id" : "44",
        "question" :"Which era did Oda Nobunaga appear?",
        "option":[
            "Azuchi-Momoyama period",
            "Meiji period",
            "Edo period",
            "Muromachi period"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Azuchi-Momoyama period"
    },
    {
        "id" : "45",
        "question" :"Which period was Genji monogatari written?",
        "option":[
            "Heian period",
            "Asuka period",
            "Meiji period",
            "Showa period"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Heian period"
    },
    {
        "id" : "46",
        "question" :"What is Beppu famous for?",
        "option":[
            "Onsen",
            "Ryokan",
            "Kimono",
            "Soba"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Onsen"
    },
    {
        "id" : "47",
        "question" :"Which are the Japan's three most scenic places?",
        "option":[
            "Mount Fuji, Matsushima, Amanohashidate",
            "Shirakawago, Amanohashidate, Miyajima",
            "Biwa Lake, Mount Fuji, Miyajima",
            "Miyajima, Amanohashidate, Matsushima"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Miyajima, Amanohashidate, Matsushima"
    },
    {
        "id" : "48",
        "question" :"Which is Japanese traditional theater?",
        "option":[
            "Noh",
            "Wayang",
            "Kathakali",
            "Yoruba Theater"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Noh"
    }
    ,
    {
        "id" : "49",
        "question" :"Where is the first capital of Japan?",
        "option":[
            "Kyoto",
            "Nara",
            "Mie",
            "Wakayama"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Nara"
    },
    {
        "id" : "50",
        "question" :"How do you call anime fan?",
        "option":[
            "Otaku",
            "Neet",
            "Hikkikomori",
            "Fujoshi"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Otaku"
    }
]